<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMMI Scientific Python Workshop</title>
    <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AMMI Scientific Python Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 07:13:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting the source code</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/setting_up/getting_the_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/setting_up/getting_the_source/</guid>
      <description>The source code for scientific Python projects is managed with git. Most scientific Python projects have their main repository available online on GitHub; for example:
NumPy: https://github.com/numpy/numpy SciPy: https://github.com/scipy/scipy NetworkX: https://github.com/networkx/networkx scikit-image: https://github.com/scikit-image/scikit-image scikit-learn: https://github.com/scikit-learn/scikit-learn Step 1: Fork the main repository Start by forking the repository. This creates a copy of the remote repository under your own GitHub account that you can both pull from and push to.
Not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve already forked a repo?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/setting_up/dev_env_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/setting_up/dev_env_setup/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have the source code, we need to set up a development environment in order to be able to do things like:
build the project run the test suite / evaluate changes locally build the documentation for the project Step 1: Installing dependencies Most projects depend on other software. Installing and managing these dependencies can be a daunting task until you&amp;rsquo;re used to it. Fortunately, there are some straight-forward best-practices to help guide the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/about_me/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/about_me/background/</guid>
      <description>My background is in nuclear engineering, specifically radiation instrumentation &amp;mdash; devices to measure and image of sources of ionizing radiation. The type of 3D radiation imaging that I studied has applications in environmental monitoring:
3D Radiation Mapping in Fukushima.Right: Aerial view of measurement area. Left: 3D gamma-ray image reconstruction &amp;mdash; Red line = path of imager through the scene, B/W dots = 3D point cloud model of the scene, Heatmap = image reconstruction; color scale corresponds to relative reconstructed intensity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSS for scientific research</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/oss_dev_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/oss_dev_model/</guid>
      <description>Scientific research depends on the effective communication of new ideas, methods, and results. Other researchers must be able to understand your ideas and reproduce your results in order to critique and expand upon your work. The open source development model, based on distributed version control (like git) and permissive licenses guarantee that everyone has equal access to others&amp;rsquo; work and can verify and build upon it without limitation.
More and more, modern research involves the development of software to implement and explore new ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scientific Python Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/about_me/ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 07:19:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/about_me/ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>In general, I am interested in the scientific Python ecosystem, i.e. the collection of open-source Python libraries that are the cornerstone of modern science, engineering, and research:
Scientific Python EcosystemA visualization of the scientific Python ecosystem. From a nature methods paper on array programming with NumPy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/homework/</guid>
      <description>A fitting meme | attribution: https://twitter.com/designuxui/status/490179377099845632 Now it&amp;rsquo;s your turn! We&amp;rsquo;ve layed out the basics of how to get the source code and spin up a working development environment, but like most things &amp;mdash; the devil is in the details 😄. In preparation for tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;d like you to pick a Python package and try setting up a development environment!
You can choose whichever package you&amp;rsquo;d like - I&amp;rsquo;d recommend maybe choosing one that you use often (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Benefits Others</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/benefits_others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/benefits_others/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways that contributing to open-source software benefits other researchers:
Accessibility Contributing to open-source software packages makes your work accessible to anyone with an internet connection!
Traditional publishing media such as scientific journals or conferences often require access fees or have limited attendance numbers. Effective Communication Well-written Python code is often among the most effective ways to communicate! For example, here&amp;rsquo;s the mathematical formula for a List-mode Maximum Likelihood Expectation Maximization algorithm used for image reconstruction:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Benefits You</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/benefits_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/why_oss/benefits_you/</guid>
      <description>At first glance, it may seem counter-intuitive that contributing to open source software benefits the contributor, but this is true in many ways! Here are just a few examples:
Becoming a better developer One of the best ways to improve your own coding ability is by reading code written by others. At face value this seems like simple advice, but the first time you sit down and try to just read some code, you&amp;rsquo;ll realize this isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/preparation/survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 07:19:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/preparation/survey/</guid>
      <description>AMMI Students Please complete the following survey to help the mentors prepare content for the workshop. Having some basic information about the workflows and development practices you&amp;rsquo;re most familiar with will help us tailor the workshop to ensure that you get the most out of it! Personal information is not being collected! All answers to the survey will remain completely anonymous and the aggregate results will not be shared with anyone except the workshop mentors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution Types</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/contribution_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/contribution_types/</guid>
      <description>There are many different ways that one can contribute to open source projects. In this workshop we&amp;rsquo;re focused mostly on the various ways that you can contribute as a developer.
Developer Contributions There are three main ways that you can contribute to an open source software project as a developer:
Submitting new code (via pull requests) Opening issues Reviewing others&amp;rsquo; code Submitting Pull Requests It&amp;rsquo;s obvious how submitting new code contributes to the development of a library, though it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that not every PR has to be new functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/anatomy/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/anatomy/documentation/</guid>
      <description>Documentation is an important part of any software project, especially since it&amp;rsquo;s usually the first thing that newcomers see! It&amp;rsquo;s so important in fact, that many projects have sub-projects or teams1 specifically dedicated to the documentation.
Documentation for Python projects Python projects typically2 use Sphinx to generate the documentation. In two sentences or less, Sphinx is a documentation generation engine that converts the content written in a markup language to various other outputs, including html which can then be published to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests</title>
      <link>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/anatomy/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bids-numpy.github.io/workshop_site_AIMS_2021/day_1/getting_started/anatomy/testing/</guid>
      <description>The collection of all tests that are included in the software package, often referred to collectively as the test suite. The test suite is an important part of any software project, but this is especially true for open source software. Tests help define expected behavior, and are extremely helpful in detecting unexpected behavior changes. Any time you make a change to an existing project, you should always run the test suite to check that your changes have not changed behavior in a way that would be incompatible with the existing software1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
